Guide to the Mabel Dodge Luhan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1905-1954; Series I; 17.31; (42 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Hagerman, Herbert J., 1925, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 443)
    - Halsman, Philippe, 1948-49 (Box 16, Folder 444)
    - Hapgood, Beatrice, 1933-34 (Box 16, Folder 445)
    - Hapgood, Charles H., 1929-37 (Box 16, Folder 446)
    - Hapgood, [Emilie?], 1916, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 447)
      Includes enclosure
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1913-43, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 448-456)
      Includes letter to John Chamberlain and notes from Neith Boyce
      See also: Boyce, Neith, Box 3, folders 90-99
    - Hapgood, Hutchins, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 457-460)
    - [Hapgood?], Miriam, 1942-50, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 461)
    - Hapgood, Neith
      See: Boyce, Neith, Box 3, folders 90-99
    - Harcourt, Alfred
      See: Harcourt Brace & Company, Box 17, folders 462-466
    - Harcourt Brace & Company, 1929-53, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 462-466)
      Includes letters from MDL and correspondence between Harcourt and Melville H. Cane
      See also: Scrapbooks, "Edge of Taos Desert," Box 83, folder 2252
      See also: Scrapbooks, "Movers & Shakers," Box 93, folder 2262
    - Harding, M. Esther, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 467)
    - Hardt, Albert, 1913, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 468)
    - Hare, Elizabeth Sage, 1917-30, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 469-470)
    - Harper's Weekly, 1913 Oct 8 (Box 17, Folder 471)
    - Harrington, M. Raymond (Box 17, Folder 472)
    - Harris, Frank, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 473)
    - Harris, Henriette, 1943-51, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 474)
    - Hart, James D., 1953 Dec 16 (Box 17, Folder 475)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1914-16, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 476)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Arthur Brisbane..." (leaves 131-138), Box 50, folder 1403
    - Harvard College Library, 1940 Feb 5 (Box 17, Folder 477)
    - Harwood Foundation, 1924-54 (Box 17, Folder 478-479)
    - Hausner, Eric P., 1946-54, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 480-481)
      Includes letters from MDL and New Mexico Dept. of Public Welfare
    - Haweis, Stephen, 1913-52, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 482-483)
      Includes carbon of letter from John Collier to MDL
    - Heath, Ogden, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 484)
    - Heinemann (Firm), 1948 Oct 4 (Box 17, Folder 485)
    - Henderson, Alice Corbin, 1922-26, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 486-494)
    - Henderson, Rose, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 495)
    - Henderson, William Penhallow, 1922 Dec 7 (Box 18, Folder 496)
    - Heredia, Georgia Cook de (aunt), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 497)
    - Herrick, Genevieve Forbes, 1935, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 498)
    - Herron, George D[avis?], 1914 (Box 18, Folder 499)
    - Hicks, Granville
      See: Scrapbooks, "Movers & Shakers," Box 93, folder 2262
    - Higgins, Victor, 1937-47 (Box 18, Folder 500)
    - Hoagland, Willard, 1944-49, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 501)
    - Hoffman, Malvina, 1934-36 (Box 18, Folder 502)
    - Hopkins, Emma Curtis, 1917-23, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 503-510)
    - [Hoskins?], Dorothy, 1932-33, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 511)
      See also: Scrapbooks, "Intimate Memories and Letters," Box 86, folder 2255
    - House of Navajo Religion, 1939 Jan 27 (Box 18, Folder 512)
    - Hovey, Carl, 1913-51, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 513-517)
      See also: Levien, Sonya, Box 23, folders 647-649
    - Howard, Roy Wilson, 1938, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 518)
    - Howe, Marie, 1924, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 519)
    - Huebsch, B. W. (Benjamin W.), 1914, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 520)
    - Hughes, Christine, 1934, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 521)
    - Hurst, Fannie, 1938, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 522)
    - Hutchins, Robert, 1944, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 523)
    - Huxley, Aldous, 1930-51 (Box 19, Folder 524)
    - "I" General, 1932-46, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 525)
    - Ickes, Anna (Wilmarth), 1932-35 (Box 19, Folder 526)
    - Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1935 Apr 13 (Box 19, Folder 527)
    - Industrial Finance Corporation, 1914 Dec 11 (Box 19, Folder 528)
    - Institute of Ethnic Affairs (Washington, D.C.), 1952 (Box 19, Folder 529)
      Includes Southwest Indian News Letter (1952)
    - Inter-Democracy Federal Unionists (U.S.), 1940 Jan 31 (Box 19, Folder 530)
    - The International, 1914, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 531)
    - International Workers' Defense League, 1917 Apr 5 (Box 19, Folder 532)
    - Irwin, Will, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 533)
    - Isaacs, Lewis M., 1936 (Box 19, Folder 534)
      Includes carbons of letters from Edwin Arlington Robinson to MDL
    - "J" General, 1914-53, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 535)
    - J.S. Ogilvie & Company, 1914 Mar 26 (Box 19, Folder 536)
    - James, Edward, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 537)
    - James, Nancy, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 538)
    - James, Rebecca Salsbury, 1929-53, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 539-541)
      Includes letters to James from Duell, Sloan & Pearce
    - Jeffers, Donnan Call, 1933-48, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 542)
      See also: Jeffers, Garth Sherwood, Box 19, folders 543-544
    - Jeffers, Garth Sherwood, 1933-49, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 543-544)
      Includes letters from GSJ to Una Jeffers, Robinson Jeffers and Red River Valley Company, and notes from Donnan Call and Charlotte Jeffers
    - Jeffers, Robinson, 1950-51 (Box 19, Folder 545)
    - Jeffers, Una, 1930-36 (Box 20, Folder 546-554)
      Includes carbon of letter from Jeffers to [Alfred?] Harcourt; letter to Jeffers from Mrs. J. Wells Smith; letter from Maynard Dixon to Robinson Jeffers; and clippings
    - Jeffers, Una, 1936-48, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 555-561)
    - Jelliffe, Belinda, 1937, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 562)
    - Jelliffe, Smith Ely, 1914-39, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 563-570)
      Includes letters from MDL, carbons and enclosures, including draft of "Ballad of a Bad Girl"
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters to Accompany Volume VI of Intimate Memories" (leaf 438), Box 52, folder 1406
    - John Reed Clubs of the West, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 571)
    - Johnson, Burges, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 572)
    - Johnson, Grace Mott, 1923-33 (Box 21, Folder 573)
    - Johnson, Walter Willard ("Spud"), 1923-52, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 574-579)
      See also: New Mexico Quarterly, Box 27, folder 761
    - Jones, Marjorie, 1916, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 580)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1914-54, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 581-589)
      Includes letters to Jones from Kenneth Macgowan and William Van Lennep
    - Jones, Robert Edmond (Box 21, Folder 590-592)
    - Jonson, Raymond, 1922 Jun 21 (Box 21, Folder 593)
    - Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1932 May 23 (Box 21, Folder 594)
    - "K" General, 1914-51, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 595-597)
    - Karshan, Don, 1954 Apr (Box 22, Folder 598)
    - Keating, Mary Aubrey, 1938 Dec 28 (Box 22, Folder 599)
    - Kennerley, Mitchell, 1913-16 (Box 22, Folder 600)
    - Kennington, Eric, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 601)
    - Kent, Rockwell, 1924-26 (Box 22, Folder 602)
    - Kenton, Edna, 1924-36, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 603)
    - Kepner, Arch, 1936-43, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 604)
      Includes letter to Kepner from Alice Hutchins Drake
    - Kiker, Henry, 1936-54, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 605-606)
      Includes letters from MDL and R. Howard Brandenburg and notes by Henry Kiker Jr.
    - Kiker, Kathleen, 1936-53, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 607)
    - King, Georgiana Goddard, 1913, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 608)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaf 260), Box 51, folder 1404
    - King, Judson, 1923 Jan 22 (Box 22, Folder 609)
    - Kiolin, Maude, 1952-53, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 610)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1934 Jul 11 (Box 22, Folder 611)
    - Kling, Ralph André, 1944-46 (Box 22, Folder 612)
    - Knee, Ernest, 1935-46, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 613)
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1927, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 614)
    - Kuppers, Peter, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 615)
    - Kuster, Gabrielle, 1930-35, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 616)
    - Kuttner, Alfred, 1914-16, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 617)
    - "L" General, 1912-52, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 618-620)
      Includes photograph and carbon from MDL to "Dr. Lovelace" with enclosure to [Abraham Arden] Brill
    - Lacher, Gisella, 1928-54, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 621-628)
    - La Farge, Oliver
    - Lanier, Henry W., 1949 (Box 23, Folder 629)
    - Larsson, Raymond Ellsworth, 1952 Sep 9 (Box 23, Folder 630)
    - Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1926, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 631)
      Includes carbon from MDL and note from Frieda Lawrence
    - Lawrence, Frieda von Richthofen, 1922-56, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 632-640)
      Includes notes from Angelino Ravagli
      See also: Lawrence, D. H., Box 23, folder 631
    - Lawrence, Frieda von Richthofen, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 641)
    - Leaden, Leo R., 1921-25, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 642)
    - Ledoux, Louis V. (Louis Vernon), 1939 Dec 27 (Box 23, Folder 643)
    - Leech, Margaret, 1927 Jul 26 (Box 23, Folder 644)
    - Lehman, [B. H. (Benjamin Harrison)?], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 645)
    - Levien, Arthur, 1939-44, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 646)
    - Levien, Sonya, 1933-53, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 647-649)
      See also: Hovey, Carl, Box 19, folders 513-517
    - Lewis, Edith, 1929-34, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 650)
    - Lewisohn, Irene, 1925-28, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 651)
    - Lewisohn, Sam A. (Sam Adolph), 1914-51, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 652-653)
      Includes carbons between Lewisohn and John A. Francis and letters from Margaret Lewisohn
    - Light, Gertrude, 1923-41, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 654)
      Includes letter to Light from Edward M. [Fault?]
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1914-36, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 655-657)
      Includes letter from Faye Lippmann
    - Litvinov, Ivy, 1932 May 17 (Box 24, Folder 658)
      Includes poem
    - Loache, Benjamin de, 1933-53, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 659)
    - Lobb, John, 1936-46, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 660-662)
    - Loewenstein, Helga, 1936-38, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 663)
    - Loy, Mina, 1913-20, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 664-665)
    - Lueders, Edward, 1951-52 (Box 24, Folder 666)
    - Luhan, Tony, 1918-43, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 667-668)
    - Lutoslawski, Wincenty, 1933 (Box 24, Folder 669)
    - "M" General, 1911-53, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 670-678)
      Includes carbons of correspondence between O. J. Merkel and Oswald Garrison Villard and enclosures
    - MacArthur, Mary, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 679)
    - McBride, Henry, 1925-33 (Box 24, Folder 680)
    - MacDougall, Sally, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 681)
    - MacKaye, Arvia, 1922-25, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 682)
    - MacKaye, Marion, 1916-22, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 683)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, Miscel[l]aneous Letters (1915 & 1916)" (leaf 258), Box 52, folder 1407
    - MacKaye, Percy, 1915-24 (Box 25, Folder 684)
    - MacMahon, F. X. Tobar de, 1917 Sep (Box 25, Folder 685)
    - MacMillan, Mary [Louise?], 1932 Apr 8 (Box 25, Folder 686)
    - Macmillan Company, 1917-47, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 687)
    - [Mafoney?], Laurence A., 1936 (Box 25, Folder 688)
    - Manby, A. R., 1919-22 (Box 25, Folder 689)
    - Marcy, Everett, 1928-47, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 690-692)
      Includes photographs and carbon of Swami Prabhavananda's "Shankara's Philosophy of Non-Dualism"
    - Marcy, [Jamie?], 1948, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 693)
      Includes letter from MDL and photographs
    - Marin, John, 1929-35 (Box 25, Folder 694)
    - Marinoff, Fania
      See: Van Vechten, Fania Marinoff, Box 36, folder 1035
    - Marot, Helen, 1915-24, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 695)
    - The Masses, 1915-16 (Box 25, Folder 696)
    - Masters, Herbert, 1940 Jan 22 (Box 25, Folder 697)
    - Mauldin, Bill, [1948?] Jun 1 (Box 25, Folder 698)
      Includes letter to Mauldin from Louis DeJean
    - Mayfield, John S., 1932 Nov 14 (Box 25, Folder 699)
    - Meem, John Gaw, 1936 Nov 24 (Box 25, Folder 700)
    - Mellen, Sarah, 1943-46 (Box 25, Folder 701)
    - Menninger, Karl [A.?], 1940-41 (Box 25, Folder 702)
    - Merz, Max
      See: Duncan, Elizabeth, Box 10, folders 277-279
      See: Elizabeth Duncan School, Box 10, folders 289-296
    - Metcalf, Addison M., 1952-53 (Box 25, Folder 703)
    - Metropolitan
      See: Hovey, Carl, Box 19, folders 513-517
    - Meyers, Ralph, 1936-45, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 704)
    - Meyers, Rowena, 1938, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 705)
      Includes notes from MDL
      See also: Meyers, Ralph, Box 25, folder 704
    - Mihan, Leo B., 1923-29, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 706-711)
      Includes note from MDL and typescript copies
    - Millard, Everett L., 1923 Aug 1 (Box 25, Folder 712)
    - Millett, Fred Benjamin, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 713)
    - Millicent A. Rogers Foundation, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 714)
    - Mitchell, Basil, 1947 Sep 8 (Box 26, Folder 715)
    - Mitchison, Naomi, 1935-36, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 716-717)
      Includes carbon manuscript "The Facts about Scottsboro"
    - Momaday, Natachee [Scott?], 1945 Oct 26 (Box 26, Folder 718)
    - Monroe, Harriet, 1914 (Box 26, Folder 719)
      See also: Poetry, Box 28, folder 816
    - Montague, Joseph E. (stepfather), 1917-33 (Box 26, Folder 720)
    - Montague, Sara Cook Ganson (mother), 1905-32, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 721-723)
      Includes postcards from MDL with photographs
    - Moore, Marianne, 1926-30 (Box 26, Folder 724)
      See also: The Dial, Box 8, folder 236
    - Moore, Virginia
      See: Scrapbooks, "Edge of Taos Desert," Box 83, folder 2252
    - Morawetz, Victor, 1923 Jan 11 (Box 26, Folder 725)
    - Morrill, Claire, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 726)
    - Morristown School (Morristown, N.J.), 1914-17 (Box 26, Folder 727-728)
    - Mountsier, Robert, 1922 (Box 26, Folder 729)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1936 Mar 17 (Box 26, Folder 730)
    - Murphy, Carolyn Cushman, 1922-23, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 731)
      Includes translation of poem by Ho Ling Pee
    - Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), 1933 (Box 26, Folder 732)
    - Museum of New Mexico, 1921 Aug 16 (Box 26, Folder 733)
    - Museum of the American Indian, 1938 May 9 (Box 26, Folder 734)
    - Myerberg, Adrienne, 1938, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 735)
      See also: Myerberg, Michael, Box 26, folder 736
    - Myerberg, Michael, 1938-43, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 736)
    - Myers, Gustavus, 1914, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 737)
    - "N" General, 1914-52, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 738)
    - The Nation, 1923-35 (Box 26, Folder 739)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1914 Jan 16 (Box 26, Folder 740)
    - National Birth Control League, 1916 Mar 2 (Box 26, Folder 741)
    - National Cash Register Company, 1917 Oct 30 (Box 26, Folder 742)
    - National Geographic Society (U.S.), 1936 Jul 6 (Box 26, Folder 743)
    - National Popular Government League, 1923 Jan (Box 26, Folder 744)
    - Native American Indian material, 1920-46, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 745-752)
      Includes correspondence and documents related chiefly to the Pueblo community in New Mexico, with the American Indian Defense Association, Zitkala-Sa, Sophie D. Aberle, John Collier, Harold L. Ickes, Oliver La Farge, Henry Kiker, Senator Elmer Thomas and others
    - Naumburg, Margaret, 1925-29 (Box 27, Folder 753)
    - Nehls, Edward, 1952 Feb 21 (Box 27, Folder 754)
    - Neumann, J. B., 1925 Apr 10 (Box 27, Folder 755)
    - New Democracy, 1934 Nov 28 (Box 27, Folder 756)
    - The New English Weekly
      See: Orage, A. R. (Alfred Richard), Box 27, folders 786-787
    - New Mexico Association on Indian Affairs, 1922 Dec 27 (Box 27, Folder 757)
    - New Mexico. Bureau of Revenue, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 758)
    - New Mexico College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts, 1946-48 (Box 27, Folder 759)
    - New Mexico. Executive Office, 1936-51 (Box 27, Folder 760)
    - New Mexico Quarterly, 1950-51, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 761)
      Includes note from MDL and carbon from NMQ to Frank Waters
      See also: Waters, Frank, Box 37, folders 1058-1078
      See also: Ortega, Joaquín, Box 27, folder 789
    - New Mexico State Penitentiary, 1944-45 (Box 27, Folder 762)
      Includes carbon to Juan D. Martinez
    - The New Republic, 1925-27 (Box 27, Folder 763)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-17" (leaves 269 and 311), Box 51, folder 1405
    - New Review, 1915 Apr 16 (Box 27, Folder 764)
    - New York Evening Journal, 1917 Sep 12 (Box 27, Folder 765)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1932-33 (Box 27, Folder 766)
    - New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Correction, 1914 May 6 (Box 27, Folder 767)
    - New York Telephone Company, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 768)
    - New York World's Fair (1939-1940), 1938-39 (Box 27, Folder 769)
    - The New Yorker, 1952 Jun 30 (Box 27, Folder 770)
    - Noguchi, Isamu, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 771)
    - Norman, Da Loria, 1916 May 20 (Box 27, Folder 772)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-1917" (leaves 93-107), Box 51, folder 1405
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1937-47, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 773)
    - Nowell, Elizabeth, 1949 Mar 29 (Box 27, Folder 774)
    - "O" General, 1917-52, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 775-777)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1925-52, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 778-782)
    - Older, Mrs. Fremont; Older, Fremont, 1924-39, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 783)
      Includes letter to Older from Raymond Arnesby and photographs
    - Oliver, Mary, 1935-53, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 784)
      See also: "Lawrence Vol. II," Box 88, folder 2257
    - O'Neill, Eugene, 1921 (Box 27, Folder 785)
    - Orage, A. R. (Alfred Richard), 1925-33, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 786-787)
      Includes letter from "Jessie"
    - Orioli, [Giuseppe?], 1928 Jul 3 (Box 27, Folder 788)
    - Ortega, Joaquín, 1951 Jul 11 (Box 27, Folder 789)
    - Otis, Ray, 1931-36, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 790)
    - "P" General, 1914-52, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 791-794)
    - Paget, W.
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Miscel[l]aneous Letters (1915 & 1916)" (leaf 188), Box 52, folder 1407
    - Paget-Fredericks, J., n.d. (Box 28, Folder 795)
    - Palms, 1923-24, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 796)
    - Pandit, S. G., 1939, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 797)
    - Parker, Dorothy, 1945 Feb 15 (Box 28, Folder 798)
    - Parker, Robert Allerton
      See: Current Opinion, Box 7, folder 213
    - Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1922-39 (Box 28, Folder 799-800)
      Includes carbon of letter from Parsons to "Governor and Council of Taos"
    - Pascin, Jules, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 801)
    - Patterson, Hank, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 802)
      Includes printed music to "Hopi Lullaby" and photographs
    - Pawlowska, Yoï, 1935 Apr 8 (Box 28, Folder 803)
    - Pearce, T. M. [Thomas Matthews?], 1932, 1944 (Box 28, Folder 804)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1953 Jul 8 (Box 28, Folder 805)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., 1940 Jan 6 (Box 28, Folder 806)
    - Pedersen, Bethsabe, 1946-47 (Box 28, Folder 807)
    - Pelton, Agnes, 1921-38, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 808)
    - People's Institute (New York, N.Y.), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 809)
    - Perkins, Francis, 1939, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 810)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes carbon from MDL
    - Perry, George Sessions, 1943 Jan 24 (Box 28, Folder 811)
    - Peters, Fritz, 1934-53 (Box 28, Folder 812)
    - Phillips, Bert [Geer?], 1948 Sep (Box 28, Folder 813)
    - Phillips, Howard S., 1932-37, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 814)
    - Picabia, F.[rancis?]
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-1917" (leaf 407), Box 51, folder 1405
    - Pijoan, Michel, 1942 Nov 25 (Box 28, Folder 815)
    - Poetry, 1925 Jul (Box 28, Folder 816)
      See also: Monroe, Harriet, Box 26, folder 719
    - Pond, Ashley, 1941-42, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 817)
    - Potter, Grace, 1925, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 818)
    - Powys, John Cowper, 1935-37 (Box 28, Folder 819)
    - Priest, Alan, 1938-47 (Box 28, Folder 820)
    - Prince, "Dr.", 1914 (Box 28, Folder 821)
      Copy of letter from MDL
    - Prinzhorn, Hans, 1929-33 (Box 28, Folder 822)
    - Provincetown Playhouse (New York, N.Y.), 1924 (Box 28, Folder 823)
    - Quinton, Cornelia B. Sage, 1923-51, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 824)
    - "R" General, 1914-53, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 825-829)
    - Rand School of Social Science, 1917 Apr 13 (Box 29, Folder 830)
    - Random House (Firm), 1938-40 (Box 29, Folder 831)
    - Rascoe, Burton, 1933 Jul 25 (Box 29, Folder 832)
    - Rauh, Ida, 1914-42, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 833-835)
    - Ravagli, Angelino, 1931-53 (Box 29, Folder 836)
      See also: Lawrence, Frieda von Richthofen, Box 23, folders 632-640
    - Reed, John (1887-1920), 1914-15, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 837-839)
      Includes letters from MDL and Hutchins Hapgood and photographs
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaf 32), Box 51, folder 1404
    - Reh, Emma, 1930-38 (Box 29, Folder 840-841)
    - Reis, Claire R. (Claire Raphael), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 842)
    - Renaudes, Lisa des, 1936-54, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 843-849)
      Includes notes from MDL and Carl Hovey and enclosures
    - Renehan & Gilbert, 1922-24 (Box 29, Folder 850)
    - Ribak, Louis, 1948 Dec 10 (Box 29, Folder 851)
    - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1913-33, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 852-855)
      See also: Isaacs, Lewis M., Box 19, folder 534
    - Rodakiewicz, Henwar, 1940-47, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 856)
    - Rodakiewicz, Peggy, 1939-40 (Box 30, Folder 857)
    - Roe, Gilbert E., 1914-16 (Box 30, Folder 858-859)
      Includes carbon from Roe to Endicott P. Saltonstall and "Statement of Mrs Mabel Dodge"
    - Rogers, John William, 1934-47 (Box 30, Folder 860)
    - Rogers, Millicent, 1947-52, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 861-862)
    - Rogers, Robert [Emmons?], 1914-25, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 863-864)
    - Rompapas, John, 1913-14, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 865)
    - Ronnenbeck, Arnold, 1925-45 (Box 30, Folder 866)
    - Ronnenbeck, Louise, 1952, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 867)
    - Rood, John, 1933 May 7 (Box 30, Folder 868)
    - Rosenbaum, Belle, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 869)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1931 Mar 30 (Box 30, Folder 870)
      See also: The American Caravan, Box 1, folder 24
    - Rothenstein, "Sir" William, 1913-39, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 871)
      Includes carbon of letter from MDL
    - Row, Arthur William, 1940, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 872)
      Includes manuscript "Home as the Root of All Evil"
    - Rudhyar, Dane, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 873)
    - The Rydal Press, 1933 Oct 7 (Box 30, Folder 874)
    - "S" General, 1913-52, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 875-880)
    - Saben, Mowry, 1914-15, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 881)
    - Sabine, Paul [Earls?], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 882)
    - Sachs, B.[ernard?], 1913
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaves 203 and 290), Box 51, folder 1404
    - Sáenz, Moisés, 1931-33 (Box 31, Folder 883)
    - Sage Books, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 884)
      See also: Alan Swallow (Firm), Box 1, folder 21
    - Sandzén, Birger
      See: Scrapbooks, "History of Taos & Its Artists," Box 85, folder 2254
    - Sanger, Margaret, 1925-41, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 885)
    - Sanger, William, 1915 Feb 28 (Box 31, Folder 886)
    - Santa Fe New Mexican, 1949 Sep 28 (Box 31, Folder 887)
    - Saturday Review, 1944-47 (Box 31, Folder 888)
    - School of American Research (Santa Fe, N.M.), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 889)
    - Schreiner, Louise, 1939-46, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 890)
    - Scola, "Kittie", 1936-40, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 891)
    - Scripps, Peggy, 1932-39, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 892)
    - Scudder, Janet, 1913-21, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 893)
    - Seltzer, Adele Szold, 1924-25 (Box 31, Folder 894)
    - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley, 1922-54, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 895-901)
    - Seton, Ernest Thompson
      See: Scrapbooks, "Winter in Taos," Box 97, folder 2266
    - Shelby, Clarence Levi, 1935, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 902)
    - Sheldon, Edward, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 903)
    - Sickles, [Daniel Edgar?], 1913, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 904)
    - Simms, Ruth [Hanna McCormick?], 1934 Oct 19 (Box 31, Folder 905)
    - Simonson, Lee, 1933-34, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 906)